Emma Scott

emmajane1276@gmail.com • 50 Copley Drive, Sunderland, SR3 1PQ • 07554017182

Summary

• Experienced primary teacher ready to excel in IT and technology.

Strengths

• Organisation & Administration

Strong organisational skills, and a proven ability to work independently, to take initiative, to anticipate and plan, and to manage and prioritise own workload and manage staff within a team.

Proven ability to meet multiple work deadlines simultaneously, while working in a busy environment. Effective management of numerous competing demands, balancing the planning and delivery of lessons, marking and feedback, management of pupils, management and analysis of data, and communicating with parents and stakeholders.

IT & Communications

Accomplished in office IT systems, including e-mail, the web, MS Office applications such as Word, Excel, Access, and PowerPoint, Google Educator suite including Google Classroom, Scholar Pack management information system.

Proven ability to manage the social media channels of the school.

Currently developing an understanding and practical application of Python, HTML and JavaScript via City of Bristol level 5 diploma in Web Applications Development.

Problem Solving & Initiative

Excellent skills in identifying problems and thinking laterally to solve them in a timely and thorough manner. Determination to complete projects to a high standard. Flexible and adaptable with a willingness to learn new skills.

Analytical skills

Excellent numerical skills and the ability to manipulate and present data using spreadsheets. Advanced skills in gap analysis of pupil achievement figures.

Interpersonal skills

Proven ability to work collaboratively with staff at all levels, including academics and administrative staff. Good listening skills to understand customer concerns. Diligent, honesty and integrity.

Employment

09.99 - 05/22:

Class Teacher (Primary) - Hasting Hill Academy (part of WISE Academy Trust)

• ROLES:

Dec 2012 – present Computing Leader

Nov 2018 – present OPAL (Outdoor Play and Learning) Lead Team.

2016 - 2020 Mentor for Schools Direct students.

Jan 2018 - Oct 2018 Acting KS1 SENDCo (Special Education Needs and Disabilities Co-ordinator)

Fixed term

Dec 2012 - Dec 2016 KS1 Team Leader - IT/Science Leader

09.95-08.96:

Au Pair in America - Fixed term, 1 Year Gap Scheme

Education

City of Bristol College

(March 2022- present)

Level 5 diploma in Web Applications Development

University of Sunderland

(1996-1999)

BA (Hons) Primary Education with Qualified Teacher Status, 2:2,

City of Sunderland College

(2004-2005)

AS Level Psychology, Grade B

Arthur Mellows Village College, Peterborough

(1993-1995)

A-Levels:

- Geography (B)
- English Language (C)
- History (D)

Arthur Mellows Village College, Peterborough

(1988-1993)

10 GCSEs Grades A-C, including

- English Language (B)
- Mathematics (C)
- English Literature (C)

Hobbies

To pursue a career in computing, I am studying for a Level 5 diploma in Web Applications Development with Bristol College, having completed a Coding Kickstarter course in Python with Code First Girls. In my spare time I enjoy being outdoors, walking with my family or gardening – seeing things grow and develop and learning new skills. I am a sociable person and enjoy supporting young people as a volunteer helper at Scouts.